But wait, there's more.
잠깐만요, 더 있어요
We need to add some more to the user interface just to make it look more cool.
사용자 인터페이스에 추가해야 더 멋져 보일 거예요
And so I put a little bit more work into this, and it's not particularly worth going through the code
비트 박스에 좀 더 공을 들였어요 코드를 그렇게 상세히 검토할 필요는 없어요
in that much detail other than to really show you what, what I came up with.
제가 생각해낸 걸 보여드리기 위한 것 외에는요
But it occurred to me that whilst it is satisfactory to see the log messages appearing so you can watch
하지만 로그 메시지가 나타나 상황을 볼 수 있는 게 만족스럽긴 하지만 사용자 인터페이스에
to see what's going on, it will be much nicer if we could surface them to the user interface.
표면을 만들면 훨씬 더 좋을 것 같아요
And that's a bit harder because typically the user interface with Gradio, it's a matter of making a
좀 더 어렵죠 일반적으로 그래디오의 사용자 인터페이스는 요청을 하고
request and getting back a response, but it's perfectly doable.
응답을 받는 문제지만 완벽하게 비트가 가능해요
And so whilst it's not necessarily worth us going through exactly how I approached it, but the I've
제가 접근한 방식을 살펴볼 필요는 없지만 이제 새로운 파일로
now turned to a new, uh, um, file, a new module called prices.
넘어가죠 가격이라는 새 모듈이에요
Right.
네
Final dot pi and in the Price is Right final.
마지막 도트파이 가격 맞히기 직전이군요
I've added in some stuff at the top to handle being able to subscribe to long log messages.
위에 몇 가지를 추가했어요 긴 로그 메시지를 구독할 수 있도록요
Um, and then I've thrown in just a little bit of extra stuff as well.
그리고 비트를 좀 더 추가했어요
So with that in mind, let's just create a new terminal window and have a look at this user interface
그걸 염두에 두고 새 터미널 창을 만들어 사용자 인터페이스를
now.
보죠
So we can say um, Python price.
파이썬 가격이라고 할 수 있죠
Oh sorry I need to activate my conda environment.
콘다 환경을 활성화해야 해요
Obviously conda activate LMS.
콘다가 LMS를 활성화한 게 분명해요
And now now we can say python price is right final.py.
파이썬 을 사용하면 최종 가격이라고 할 수 있죠 네
And we can see what comes up.
뭐가 나오는지 보죠
Uh so again it thinks for a little while.
그래서 한동안 생각을 해요
Up it comes.
올라와요
And you're going to notice 1 or 2 changes here.
여기 1, 2개의 변화가 보이시죠
Uh, so first of all, uh, as I promised, we've got this very attractive looking, uh, log here that
먼저, 말씀드렸듯이 여기 아주 매력적인 로그가 있는데요, 진행 상황을 보여주고,
shows you what's going on and allows you to look across the different, uh, agents as they run, see
서로 다른 에이전트들이 운영되는 동안 누가 무엇을 하는지 볼 수
who is doing what.
있죠
Uh, as before, we have our table up here, and that's going to allow us.
아까처럼 테이블은 여기 위에 있어요
I just clicked on that and I saw out of the corner of my eye that of course I got a push notification
클릭을 했더니 제 곁눈질로 푸시 알림이 바로 뜨는
right away.
걸 봤어요
Uh, and what do we have here?
이건 또 뭐죠?
Well, what we have here is a 3D representation of our chroma database that's being used to look up
이건 크로마 데이터베이스의 3D 모형입니다 프론티어
the products to send to the frontier model when it appears over here.
모델에 보낼 제품을 찾는 데 사용되죠
Uh, now, I know what you're thinking.
무슨 생각 하시는지 알아요
You're thinking, okay, but what's the business purpose of having this particular rag knowledge store
이 사용자 인터페이스에 이 특정 래그 지식 저장소가 나타나는 비즈니스
being surfaced on this user interface?
목적이 뭘까 생각하죠
Uh, and it's an important question and an important answer.
중요한 질문이자 중요한 대답이에요
Um, is that there's no purpose whatsoever.
목적이 전혀 없다는 거예요
No purpose to having this diagram.
이 도표를 왜 갖고 있죠?
It just looks great.
정말 멋져요
And I want it to.
그러길 바라요
And it's my course.
제 수업이고요
And so I'll do it if I want to.
그러니 하고 싶으면 해야죠
Uh, so yeah, I mean, in all seriousness there, uh, it was nice to be able to surface some data
네, 정말 진지하게 말씀드리면 데이터를 표면화할 수 있어서 좋았고 Gadio 사용자
and be able to illustrate how easy it is to get a plot to show on a Gradio user interface.
인터페이스에서 줄거리를 보여주는 게 얼마나 쉬운지 설명할 수 있어서 좋았어요
Um, but, uh, this this is running, uh, just, uh, in to show off.
하지만 이 차는 자랑하려고 달리는 거예요
What would perhaps be useful over time is to show in this the memory and actually be able to show in
시간이 흐르면 메모리에서 보여주는 게 유용할 거예요 벡터 포맷으로 메모리의 여러 지점을
vector format the different points on the memory, and you can hover over it and see it.
보여주는 거죠 마우스로 가리키면 보이고요
So maybe I'll make that adjustment myself, but or you could do it for me and push the code that would
제가 직접 조정할 수도 있지만 아니면 비트가 해줘서 코드를 푸시해 이걸
make this a little bit more useful and less of a gratuitous change.
좀 더 유용하게 만들고 불필요한 변화는 줄여줄 수도 있죠
Now, the other thing that you might have noticed while I've been speaking is that the memory suddenly
제가 말하는 동안 눈치챘을지도 모르는 또 다른 건 갑자기 메모리가
went blank, and you may be wondering why on earth did the memory go blank?
백지화됐다는 겁니다 왜 메모리가 백지화됐는지 궁금하실 거예요
And the reason the memory went blank is, of course, because the run has kicked off over here.
메모리가 빈 이유는 물론 여기서 실행이 시작됐기 때문이죠
And actually, again, there are ways around this, but right now, when the run is in progress, that
이것도 비트는 방법이 있지만 현재는 실행이 진행 중일 때 테이블이 비어있다가
table goes blank and then it will repopulate when the run completes, which is a bit janky and can be
실행이 완료되면 다시 채워질 겁니다 좀 엉성하지만 고칠 수 있죠
fixed.
UI 개선을 위한 연습이 될 수 있어요
Um, but you can see right now it's got to the point where it's calling modal.
하지만 지금은 모듈이라고 부르는 지점에 이르렀어요
And so modal will be warming up.
그래서 수단이 준비 운동을 하는 거죠
So with that, because this will take a minute, I will pause and I will come back when it has completed.
시간이 좀 걸리기 때문에 일시 정지하고 완료되면 다시 돌아오죠
See you then.
그때 봐요